Inventory of the Imre Pozsgay papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Alphabetical file, 1953-1995 and undated (Box 58-88)
  - Tömegkommunikációs Kutatóközpont, 1984-1988 and undated (Folder 87)
    correspondence, reports, research papers, articles
  - Tóth, Károly, Bishop, 1983-1986 (Folder 87)
  - Überhaupt, 1972 (Folder 87-88)
  - Vajdasági Magyarok Demokratikus Közössége, 1990-1991 (Folder 88)
  - Vass, László, undated (Folder 88)
  - Vay Ádám Múzeum, 1988 (Folder 88)
  - Vennes, Aranka, 1987-1991 (Folder 88)
  - Veszeley, Béla, 1991 (Folder 88)
  - Veszprém, 9 January 1986 (Folder 88)
    handwritten notes and questions
  - Virt, László, 1986 (Folder 88)
  - Weörös, Sándor, undated (Folder 88)
    A kétfejű fenevad, a typescript, and a report on the typescript
  - World Assembly for Peace and Life, Against Nuclear War, Prague, 1983 (Folder 88)
- Writings by and about Imre Pozsgay, circa 1975-1995 (Box 88-98)
  handwritten and typewritten manuscripts and notes, published materials, interviews
  - Imre Pozsgay's curricula vitae (in English) (Folder 88)
  - Interviews with Imre Pozsgay, writings about Imre Pozsgay (Folder 88-89)
    typescripts, photocopies of published materials, interview questions
  - Print proofs, photocopies of published materials, and publications about, by, or probably by, Imre Pozsgay (Folder 89)
  - Augusztus 20-án, 1983 and undated (Folder 89)
    an article by Imre Pozsgay, with correspondence and additional materials attached
  - An essay and a research paper on nationalism, with correspondence attached (Folder 90)
  - Writings by Imre Pozsgay, with correspondence attached (Folder 90)
  - Könyv, 1992. július 30 (Folder 90)
  - Handwritten and typewritten manuscripts by, or probably by, Imre Pozsgay (Folder 91-94)
    speeches, essays, reports, other documents
  - Handwritten notes, mostly records of meetings (Folder 94-98)
- Miscellany, circa 1975-1995 (Box 98-101)
  research papers, reports, literary writings, itineraries, fragments of documents, promotional materials, invitations, publications, other documents
- Increment 2009, 1968-2005 (Box 102-116)
  The series is organized into 13 subseries: VHS tapes and DVD discs, Photographs, Writings by or about Pozsgay, Államminiszter (Minister of State) file, István Bibó file, Hazafias Népfront documents, Magyar Demokrata Fórum documents, Magyarországi Szociáldemokrata Párt documents, Magyar Szocialista Munkás Párt documents, Magyar Szocialista Párt documents, Nemzeti Demokrata Szövetség documents, Országgyũlés (Parliament) file, and Miscellany. VHS tapes and DVD discs, and Photographs, are arranged generally in the original order. All other series are arranged chronologically and some also thematically.
  - VHS tapes and DVD discs, circa 1985-2005 (Folder 102)
    Contains Pozsgay's presentations, interviews; a documentary entitled Szamizdatos évek; and a two-part documentary entitled 1956: A forradalom emlékezete
    Arranged generally in the original order
  - Photographs, circa 1983-1989 (Folder 103: 1)
    Contains photographs of Pozsgay, mostly at official domestic and international meetings, and scans of photographs from the Pan-European Picnic in 1989
  - Writings by or about Pozsgay, circa 1981-1997 (Folder 103-104)
    Contains typescripts, curricula vitae, publications, translations, reports, interviews, newspaper clippings
    Arranged chronologically and then thematically
    - Curricula vitae and interviews, circa 1991-1995 (Folder 103: 2)
    - Typescripts by Pozsgay, 1987-1991 and undated (Folder 103: 3)
    - Die Erde bebt, German translation of Pozsgay's memoir, 1993 (Folder 103: 4-5)
    - A report about and an interview with Pozsgay by János Dömölky, 1994 (Folder 103: 6)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1981-1992 and 1997 (Folder 103: 7-8)
    - Newspaper articles on Pozsgay's donation of his papers to the Hoover Institution Archives, 1997 (Folder 103: 9)
    - Koronatanú és tettestárs, 1998 (Folder 104: 1)
      A signed monograph
    - A rendszerváltás (k)ára, 2003 (Folder 104: 2)
  - Államminiszter (Minister of State) file, 1988-1990 (Folder 104: 3-8)
    Contains timetables for official visits, reports, correspondence, and related materials
    - Visit of President George H. W. Bush to Hungary, 1989 (Folder 104: 3)
      Contains the program of the visit
    - Center for Strategic and International Studies, correspondence, reports and related materials, 1988-1989 (Folder 104: 4)
      Contains letters from Amos A. Jordan and Zbigniew Brzezinski
    - Meeting with Canadian Parliament representatives, 1989 (Folder 104: 5)
    - Visit to France, 1989 (Folder 104: 6)
    - Meeting with Valmy Féaux, Minister-President of the French Community of Belgium, 1989 (Folder 104: 7)
    - Other materials, 1989-1990 (Folder 104: 8)
  - István Bibó file, 1983 and 1988 (Folder 104: 9-10)
    Contains a samizdat publication and a dissertation in manuscript
    Arranged chronologically
    - Bibó István 56-os írásai, samizdat publication, 1983 (Folder 104: 9)
    - Klimó, Hedvig:Kapcsolódási pontok Eötvös József és Bibó István eszmerendszerében, doctoral dissertation, 1988 (Folder 104: 10)
  - Hazafias Népfront documents, 1985-1989 (Folder 105: 1-4)
    Contains correspondence, reports and related materials
    - Hazafias Népfront documents, 1985 (Folder 105: 1)
    - Hazafias Népfront documents, 1987-1989 (Folder 105: 2)
    - Visit to China, 1986 (Folder 105: 3)
    - Károly Kisfaludy bicentenary birthday celebrations, 1988 (Folder 105: 4)
  - Magyar Demokrata Fórum documents, 1989-1992 and undated (Folder 105: 5-6)
    Contains correspondence, reports and interviews
    - Correspondence and reports, 1989-1992 and undated (Folder 105: 5)
    - Interview with Mihály Bihari and attached correspondence, 1989 (Folder 105: 6)
  - Magyarországi Szociáldemokrata Párt documents, 1990, 1994 and undated (Folder 105: 7)
    Contains party programs and related materials
  - Magyar Szocialista Munkás Párt documents, 1968-1993 and undated (Folder 105-107)
    Contains minutes of meetings, reports, correspondence, Pozsgay's speeches, printed matter and related materials
    - A Gaulle-izmus tíz esztendéje, monograph, 1968 (Folder 105: 8)
    - Reports and Pozsgay's presentations, 1981-1982 and probably 1982 (Folder 105: 9)
    - Reports, 1984 (Folder 105: 10)
    - Typescript with speeches and lectures entitled A Monori Tanácskozás, 1985. június 14-16, and an official report on the Monor meeting (Folder 105: 11)
    - Materials on the Lakitelek meeting, including a typescript of Pozsgay's speech; reports on Zbigniew Brzezinski meetings with the party representatives; other reports, speeches and similar materials, 1987 (Folder 105: 12)
    - Reports, publications and related materials, 1988 (Folder 105: 13)
    - Reports, minutes of meetings and related materials, 1989 (Folder 106: 1-14 and 107:1)
    - Reports and statements, 1991 and 1993 (Folder 107: 2)
    - Reports, undated (Folder 107: 3)
  - Magyar Szocialista Párt documents, 1989-1994 and undated (Folder 107-108)
    Contains minutes of meetings, reports, correspondence, printed matter and related materials
    - Az MSZMP XIV. - az MSZP I. kongresszusa, 1989. október 7.: Szó szerinti jegyzőkönyv, minutes of a meeting, typescript (Folder 107: 4-5)
    - Az MSZP I. kongresszusa, 1989. október 8.: Szó szerinti jegyzőkönyv, minutes of a meeting, typescript (Folder 107: 6-8)
    - Az MSZP I. kongresszusa, 1989. október 9.: Szó szerinti jegyzőkönyv, minutes of a meeting, typescript (Folder 108: 1)
    - Correspondence, reports and published matter, 1989-1990 (Folder 108: 2)
    - Collection of articles on the 1994 Hungarian general election, January 1994 (Folder 108: 3)
    - Reports, speeches and printed matter, 1994 (Folder 108: 4)
  - Nemzeti Demokrata Szövetség documents, 1991-1994 and undated (Folder 108-109)
    Contains writings in typescript by or about Pozsgay, correspondence, internal documents, printed matter and related materials
    - Correspondence, internal documents and newspaper clippings, 1991 (Folder 108: 5)
    - Correspondence, internal documents and related materials, 1992 (Folder 108: 6)
    - Internal documents, printed matter and related materials, 1993 (Folder 108: 7)
    - Correspondence, internal documents, printed matter and related materials, 1994 (Folder 108: 8)
    - Writings by or about Pozsgay and related materials, mostly typecripts, 1994 and undated (Folder 109: 1)
    - A Nemzeti Demokrata Szövetség programja, typescript, undated (Folder 109: 2)
  - Országgyũlés (Parliament) file, 1986-1993 (Folder 109)
    - Reports, correspondence and publications, 1986-1990 (Folder 109: 3)
    - Reports, correspondence and related materials, 1991 (Folder 109: 4)
    - Correspondence and reports, 1992 (Folder 109: 5)
    - Presentations, reports, correspondence and related materials, 1993 (Folder 109: 6)
  - Miscellany, 1977-1997 and undated (Folder 109-111)
    Contains articles, studies, reports, publications, student papers, correspondence and promotional materials, mostly related to contemporary Hungarian economy, history and politics
    - A lengyel ellenzék dokumentumaiból, collection of articles with an introduction by György Bence and János Kis, typescript, 1977 (Folder 109: 7)
    - Tucker, Robert C.: Személyiség és politikai vezetés, translation of his article Personality and Political Leadership, typescript, 1977 (Folder 109: 8)
    - Blm, Norbert: Modern társadalompolitikai alapelvek, translation of an article from West-Ost Journal, typescript, 1981 (Folder 109: 9)
    - Schmidt-Häuer, Christian: Mihail Gorbacsov, translation of a book, typescript, 1985 (Folder 110: 1)
    - Nowak, Stefan: A lengyel társadalom az 1980-as évek második felében - kisérlet a kztudat állapotának diagnosztizálására, translation of a study, typescript, 1987 (Folder 110: 2)
    - Lakiteleki Tanácskozás jegyzőkönyve, collection of articles, typescripts and photocopies of typescripts, 1987 (Folder 110: 3)
    - Correspondence, economic and news reports, and promotional materials, 1989 (Folder 110: 4)
    - Correspondence, economic and news reports, and promotional materials, 1990 (Folder 110: 5)
    - Teleki László Alapítvány documents, 1991 and 1993 (Folder 110: 6)
      Contains correspondence, minutes of meetings, and related materials
    - Research papers and related materials, news reports, clippings, and promotional materials, 1991 (Folder 110: 7)
    - Research papers and related materials, news reports, clippings, and promotional materials, 1991 (Folder 110: 7 and 111: 1)
    - Arrabona University in Győr, reports, 1992 (Folder 111: 2)
    - Expo '96 Budapest, 1992 (Folder 111: 3)
    - Reports, research papers and promotional materials, 1992 (Folder 111: 4)
    - Reports, research papers, correspondence and related materials, 1993 (Folder 111: 5-7)
    - Reports, research papers, correspondence and related materials, 1994 (Folder 111: 8)
    - Reports, research papers, correspondence and related materials, 1995 (Folder 112: 2)
    - Pázmány Péter Katolikus Egyetem, promotional materials, 1996 (Folder 112: 3)
    - Student papers on contemporary Hungarian politics and history, 1997 and probably 1997 (Folder 112: 4-6)
    - Research papers and related materials, undated (Folder 112: 7)
  - Printed matter, circa 1985-1995 (Folder 113-116)
    Contains miscellaneous monographs and periodicals